so this is
chasing us Jason
properly speaking is intentional
intention or volition
or volition
the word intention is normal looser
meeting including these
including these
and the best translation Chaikin it so
so
it's a little wordy here obviously with
the idea of like intention of containing
both of those things like intentions and
will can you speak briefly about what
yes well the thing is you start with
intention you start with J tonight so we
will need to reverse engineering you
will need to discern within that the
subtle forms of intentions that are the
necessary basis for intentional
intention so it's important to again not
fall into the the assumption of the
extent of view whereby you can sort of
visualize the intention and then their
intention gets doubled so it becomes
intentional intention and that's how you
I know you act in through direction you
can discern that you acted in certain
manner because you had given options and
given options given possibilities arisen
implications of within there is an
experience those applications are
already intentions
they're already intentional and then you
choose to attend certain intentions on
account of other intentions that are
equally given and based on what you've
been choosing to attend you end up
intentionally intending further and
acting out of it that's variable you
would say you don't attend to
unwholesome you attend to holes
you don't give improper attention to a
phenomena because it will bring on also
to arise you have no say in the
manifestation of phenomenon but you do
have a say in choosing to attend things
based on sensuality things based on
ill-will things based on delusion and
distraction and that's within the given
the basis of possibilities
which means within anything you can
exercise restraint oh you can access
indulgence it's entirely up to you
and that's where the practice is it's in
that middle not in trying to get rid of
things or overly explain them or or
define how they came to be in what
infraction of nanosecond that's all
irrelevant what's relevant is halfway up
in that middle whether you were
carelessly attending to it carelessly
giving rise to more sensuality on
account of choosing to the $10 in
charity in the first place and so on or
whether you're holding whether you say
no this is this is careless this
essential and then you attend the
opposite by attending the opposite the
sensuality ceases the real will ceases
the distraction disappears
so in the indian cyclopædia article that
he quotes in the last paragraph there's
one type of one to bring up it says that
to be conscious of something is no empty
you having of that something in
consciousness each phenomenon a dimensional structure
each phenomenon a dimensional structure
which analysis shows to be an
ever-widening system individually
intentional intentionally related
components so right up here in this
phenomena logical the idea of there
being structures of experience of things
yeah that's that's what we just said
it's I mean it's not wrong to describe
it like that but it's certainly not it's
not another Buddha will call up a knife
it's not something they will lead you to
the to the further understanding it's a
description they provided you with
information but it won't lead you to
further understanding because it's it's
based on external point of view you're
describing this this complex structure
of intentionality and it is accurate way
to sort of describe it but it does not
represent how its being lived and seen
which is what comes first so you can
only step outside of that structure in
your abstraction and provide pleasing
and I could a description but it's still
a description as in explanation
it still is still the assumes the
external point of view of that structure
which you cannot step outside of so
that's what I meant when I said you have
to actually look through what you have
which is your intentional action within
that you start discerning so within the
arisen enduring phenomena of
possibilities to have possibilities to
make choice you realize that how you're
making choices by choosing to attend
this on account of this and both of
which were given all of these
possibilities are given within the
choices that you would make
and that's how you start making
wholesome at the expense of on holes so
the talking about describing the
structure as the as the phenomenology
does it's it's accurate for a puta Gina
point of view but it's certainly not
something that can lead him out of the
state of being boo to Jenelle because he
keeps assuming this telephone of you
which means he of course be the actual
aspects as negative
and to preserve the actual state of
affairs this is a tension car its
simplest terms describe I was just gonna
say emphasis is there attention you
choosing to emphasize something means
has to be done at the expense of
something else
you can't emphasize everything equally
because then there is no emphasis at all
so that's why I did the attention is
like that the court pretty much and it
is one of the reasons for arising the
right view the right attention and the
right authorize it's you can't you can't
change things and make them only appear
with wholesome options and wholesome
possibilities this is beyond your reach
it's inconceivable but what you can do
is stop attending them roundly stop
attending them is mine stop attending
them with desire and lust stop attending
the amount of use of sensuality and
green so that that wait the deep talks
about is it's the weight that the you
would be responsible it's like a weight
of a habit for example there we are
coarser example of it but it's the
extension of the same principle if
you've been engaging in certain acts you
develop a habit as in you develop a
certain pressure that takes a certain
you that you can't say no to it and then
you just have to do these habits now but
you are fully responsible for generating
that pressure that weight that's now
pressing you and fundamentally that's
the principle of existence keep assuming
the ownership of it that then the life
becomes a burden becomes become
something that it's weighing on you with
all its infinite possibilities that you
kind of implicitly feel are not in your
control and they're terrifying yet you
cannot help but be pressured into that
owners shipping and sense of control
that you are fully responsible for by
giving in to desire and lost in regard
to it so you
accumulate the weight of a very
significant that's why it's hard to say
no to sensuality for example not because
it's fundamentally contains all that
weight instantaneously no it's because
you've been engaging with it for so long
that you built it up but that's why it
is also possible to undo it and overcome
it you stop engaging in the acts that
perpetuate that maintain and add more of
that weight that's what we will talk
about a burden because the things you do
you keep accumulating burden and then
you can't stop doing it so yeah it's
true you might be too pressured by the
habits but you responsible for the the
habits behind that treasure so if you
just start gradually developing strength
in terms of restraint that emphases well
you create a broader a broader
perspective from which you can choose to
emphasize things if you're fully
absorbed is just gratification of your
senses acting upon your will and so on
yeah you're just driven your emphasis is
driven by the weight that you've been
accumulating and maintaining through
careless attention but you change that
you start attending things things Kelly
okay carefully you stop feeding that
pressure and by not feeling the pressure
you actually develop a greater
perspective that and then it becomes
easier to shift the emphasis on
wholesome and expensive and also that's
why the Buddha would say the restraint
the sila the virtue comes and needs to
come first
there is simply it's not negotiable
so then is the structure of both careful
and unfair full attention fundamentally
the same as he is describing here
fundamentally the same Nike describing
what it's it's along the same lines if
it's either/or you can't have wholesome
animals so what was it then
distinguishes the careful attention at
least I guess it's whether it's rooted
in clear diversion delusion which are
the things which were the weights which
were the pressures that should not be
there but there is no first point before
which they weren't so they always have
been there but once you start once you
stop feeding them and once you
understand and they fade and they cannot
return because there is actually no room
for that type of weight in the
experience of the five aggregates in the
experience of an era
this is from the left foot no pets
though there is intention shaking us
both simple and reflexive ie position
experience there is no craving in other
words there is and there is not
intentional consciousness there is no
concept of attention craving however
different to ''tis the beginning is
parasite on the intention of the
structure described here it's necessity
is not to be deduced of intention
intention does not imply craving hard
thing yeah so parasite needs its host so
they cannot be craving without intention
but there can be intention without
craving and that craving is that that
that wait there has been beginningless
Lee perpetuated in regard to want
attention craving of sensuality sense
desires to go craving for pleasure
driving for avoiding pain all those
things that type of wait as a criteria
for your choice as in there something
painful my weight of that criteria is
avoid the pain and that's my default
action that can be undone and that's
what happens to neuron
he doesn't undo the agreeable or
disagreeable feelings but he undoes the
craving in regard to them which is then
means yeah he from the point of view of
petitioner Arvind has no feelings then
from the point of view Neutrogena which
is his only intention that he can now is
the attention effective like baby
if he was to discern how can other hand
have any tension without craving or
he'll be released the soda ban so that's
why from the point of view of the two
Jenna our hunt doesn't have intentions
have consciousness doesn't have anything
because for cartagena intentions
consciousness feelings are the things
that are fully weighted by that by that
pressure of craving and unwholesome